Brian Isaboke Nyamumbe

Information Technology Specialist

■ nyamumbebrian157@gmail.com

+254727903007

★ https://brianprofile.netlify.app/

Nairobi, Kenya

Profile

I am a passionate IT support specialist and a web developer with 1 year experience as an IT specialist. Having great skills in full stack web development; JavaScript, Node.js, React, among other skills, I aspire to work with developers and clients to make organizations reach their peak in technology.

Having in-depth understanding of diverse computer systems and networks, I am excellent in the technical aspects of IT technology thus providing support to users and making me the first point of contact for error reporting.

I have honed my follow-up, listening, and emotional intelligence skills which have enabled me to handle clients and users in whatever state they are in and act promptly when they need services offered by the organization.

Skills

Technical aspects of IT Technology

Using computer hardware, computer software and networks to organize data and information. Providing support to computer users, making me the the first point of contact for error reporting. Installing and configuring hardware and software components to ensure usability.

Keeping all systems and software up to the current release.

Managing, prioritizing any IT problems and queries, and solving technical and operational challenges in the scope of IT as reported by users and colleagues.

Network and Infrastructure Management

I am skilled in network monitoring, troubleshooting to resolve network connectivity issues, and documentation. I can provide support management of infrastructure power systems and power backup systems.

Great Communication Skills

Through working as an IT Intern, I have gained communication skills from interpersonal interactions thus enabling me to have excellent command of English (both written and spoken). Ability to communicate in foreign language (German) and express myself simply and coherently.

Web Development

I am skilled to work with the following frontend and backend web development languages; HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS and React in designing responsive websites in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Graphic Design

Proficient in using Adobe Photoshop 2021. In designing I use the aesthetics of typography and the compositional arrangement of the text, ornamentation, and imagery to convey ideas, feelings, and attitudes beyond what language alone expresses.

Microsoft Office Suite

Proficient in using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite.

Using Microsoft Word to generate different formats in accordance with the need and importance, for efficient presentation of information.

Using Microsoft Teams to combine workplace chat, meetings, notes, and attachments thus enabling collaboration and communication between the users.

Education

O1/2023 - 04/2023

Goethe Zertifikat B1
Goethe Insitut-Nairobi

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
University of Eldoret

Web Development Bootcamp
Udemy.com

Django Masterclass
Udemy.com

04/2018 - 05/2018

Certificate of Proficiency in Computer Applications

Nanyuki, Kenya

Kenya Institute of Management

Professional Experience

2021 – present Nairobi, Kenya

Web Developer and Graphics Designer

Freelancing

I am detail oriented and proactive thus working as a freelancer in designing responsive websites and graphics design in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Key responsibilities include;

- Designing website layouts.
- Thinking through the navigation of a site to provide the best user experience.
- Working in Adobe programs to create visuals, graphics, or animations.
- Understanding, creating, and testing applications for the website.
- Troubleshooting website problems.
- Staying up-to-date on technology.

05/2022 – 07/2022 Eldoret, Kenya

Information Technology Intern

Eldoret Law Courts

Through serving as an IT Intern under the ICT Department, I have gained practical skills and hands-on experience in the following areas:

- Providing technical support to computer users on the use of computer hardware and software applications.
- Computer networking and configuration to support traffic, improve network security, and increase network stability.
- Installing and upgrading computer software and hardware components to ensure usability.
- PC hardware maintenance and troubleshooting techniques to solve software issues and replace damaged hardware.
- Collecting data, establishing facts, and drawing valid conclusions to solve technical and operational challenges in the scope of IT as reported by users.
- Installing and upgrading anti-virus software to ensure security at the user level.

04/2019 – 08/2019 Nanyuki, Kenya

Hotel Steward

Kongoni Camp Hotel

Through working in the Hospitality Industry, I have gained experience in offering good customer service and discussing any issues with a wide variety of individuals and groups. I am equipped with the following skills;

Greeting and welcoming customers.

Receiving and responding to customer calls in regards to services offered by the company.

Dealing with customer complaints.

Serving food and beverages in a professional manner with high levels of customer service.

Checking with customers to ensure that they are enjoying the services and take action to correct any problems.

Languages

- English
- Swahili
- German

References

Wycliffe Ireri, *ICT Officer*, Eldoret Law Courts wyckieireri@gmail.com, +254703603017

Isabella Karani, *Teacher*, Inoro Secondary School isabkieb@yahoo.com., +254723549719

Cyrus Maina, *German Teacher*, Lanet Secondary School wairagu24@gmail.com, +254722452971